[Road to Success]
[星のように煌めく]
[Episode 5]
[第五話]
Outdoor sports—
アウトドア
cycling.
サイクリングだ
Today's goal is to burn 800 kcal.
今日の目標は 800キロカロリー消費
It should take
予想時間は
about 2 hours and 9 minutes.
２時間９分
That should be reasonable
合理的だが
but not too demanding, right?
厳しすぎない要求だろう
Why not go all the way and time it to the second?
いっそ秒単位まで決めれば
That's way too challenging.
無謀すぎるわよ
If you don't know how to ride a bike,
もし林先生が自転車に乗れないなら
you can just scoot along on one foot.
片足でペダルをこぐか
Or...
もしくは
admit defeat.
ギブアップだ
Who says I can't ride?
誰が乗れないなんて言ったのよ
Excuse me,
悪いが
show me your hand.
手を
What for?
何するの？
You're quite well-equipped.
装備だけは一人前ね
This sports watch
このスポーツウォッチは
[Cycling] [Average Pace]
[サイクリング][平均ペース]
is synced to my phone.
私のスマホと連動している
I can see your data.
君のデータが見えるんだ
Let me remind you again,
ついでにもう一度言っておく
Ms. Lin—
林先生
you can admit defeat anytime.
いつでもギブアップしていい
Don't worry.
安心して
In my whole life,
子供の頃から今まで
"admit defeat" has never been in my vocabulary.
ギブアップなんてしたことないわ
I don't know how to ride a bike at all.
自転車なんて全然乗れない
[Fifteen minutes later]
[15分後]
[Cycling] [Average Pace]
[サイクリング][平均ペース]
No movement at all.
ずっと動いてない
Looks like she really can't ride.
本当に乗れないみたいだな
A friendly reminder,
忠告しておくが
Ms. Lin—
林先生
time waits for no one.
時間は待ってくれないぞ
If you can't ride,
乗れないなら
you can admit defeat.
ギブアップしていい
To hell with it.
もういいわ
I'm going for it.
やるしかない
[Three hours later]
[３時間後]
[Cycling] [Average Pace]
[サイクリング][平均ペース]
She learned to ride that fast?
もう乗れるようになったのか
Where are you?
どこにいる
The neighborhood park.
団地の公園よ
Sister,
お姉ちゃん
you're still using training wheels?
大人なのに補助輪？
We stopped using those ages ago.
僕たちもう使ってないよ
They're my secret weapon.
これは秘密兵器なの
Pretty crafty, huh?
よく小細工するな
Sister,
お姉ちゃん
let's race and see who's faster!
誰が速いか競争しよう
Could the person in front of me,
目の前で子供たちと
who hit it off with the kids right away,
すぐに打ち解ける人が
really be the malicious Spade Q?
本当に悪意を抱くスペードのＱか？
Be careful, you kids.
気をつけて
Sister, you're too slow.
お姉ちゃん 遅いよ
♪ Two souls alike ♪
♪ 二つの魂が寄り添って ♪
How are you still this slow with four wheels?
補助輪付きなのに なんでそんなに遅いのか
With four wheels, it's harder to keep everything balanced,
補助輪があると バランス取りにくいの
♪ In the silent gravity ♪
♪ 静かな引力に導かれ ♪
so I can't go fast.
スピードが出ないわ
Come on, Sister!
お姉ちゃん 頑張って
♪ Cure my heart ♪
♪ 君のすべてで ♪
See? I passed you.
ほら 追い越しちゃった
Maybe
もしかしたら
♪ With every part of you ♪
♪ 私の孤独な心を 癒してくれた ♪
she
彼女は
didn't mean to do that?
わざとじゃなかったのかも
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 言葉はそっと ♪
♪ Like a gentle stream ♪
♪ 優しい川のように流れて ♪
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 蛍のあかりが ♪
♪ Inside of a silky dream ♪
♪ 柔らかな夢へと舞い降りる ♪
♪ We talked the whole night, breeze away ♪
♪ 夜通し語れば 夜風も静かに眠ってゆく ♪
♪ Together we set out on a long journey ♪
♪ この長い道を ♪
We won.
私たちは勝った
♪ The endless journey ♪
♪ どこまでも歩いていこう ♪
We won! We won!
やったー 勝った
Congratulations.
おめでとう
So this is what you call "a piece of cake"?
これがさっき言ってた朝飯前か
This is called cheating.
それはズルだろ
What do you know?
何も分かってないくせに
This is called strategic intelligence.
これは知恵よ
You've already been riding for 1 hour and 3 minutes,
すでに１時間３分乗って
but you've only burned 120 kcal.
120キロカロリーしか 消費してない
How is that possible?
うそ
Didn't you say two hours
２時間で800キロカロリー
would burn 800 kcal?
消費できるって言ったのに
Your heart rate is too low.
心拍数が低すぎるんだ
To raise it,
心拍数を上げるには
you need to speed up or go uphill.
加速するか坂を登るかだ
Got it.
勉強になったわ
There's nothing in this world
この世界で
that I can't learn!
私にできないことなんてない
Not riding anymore?
もうやめたか
Four wheels really are unreliable.
やっぱり補助輪はダメね
One just flew off.
一つ取れちゃったし
You fell?
転んだのか
I have a cramp.
足がつったわ
Sit.
座って
What are you doing?
何するの
Bear with it a little.
少し我慢しろ
It'll hurt a bit.
ちょっと痛いぞ
Do you know what you're doing?
本当にできるの？
Maybe I should go find a bonesetter instead.
やっぱり接骨院に行くわ
There.
治った
Try moving it now.
試してみて
[Calories: 433 kcal] [Average Heart Rate: 146 bpm]
[433カロリー] [平均心拍数 146拍/分]
Now, you can keep riding with a busted leg like that.
不屈の精神でまだ乗れるだろ
Still 367 kcal to go.
あと367キロカロリーだ
My leg just cramped up!
足がつったのよ
Do you have any humanity left?
それでも人間なの？
I'm hungry.
お腹空いた
I need to eat first.
先にご飯にしよう
I'll figure something out after I'm full.
食べてから考えるわ
So, Ms. Lin, are you admitting defeat?
林先生 負けを認めるんだな
That's right. I admit defeat.
そうよ 負けを認めるわ
Even though I lost this morning,
午前は負けたけど
that doesn't mean you'll win this afternoon.
午後はあなたの勝ちとは限らないわ
Just you wait.
見てて
Who are you trying to scare?
誰を脅してるんだ
Trying to buy more time?
時間稼ぎか？
Yeah.
そうよ
So what?
文句ある？
We're here.
着いた
It's that place ahead.
あそこのお店
How about we go somewhere else?
別の店にしないか？
Why?
どうして
Their wontons are really good.
ここのワンタン美味しいの
There's still 1 minute and 45 seconds until 12 o'clock.
12時まであと１分45秒ある
It's still morning,
まだ午前中だ
so you have to listen to me.
私の言うことを聞け
-I'll find a better restaurant... -Ma'am!
- もっと良い食事場所を探す - ボス
I'm here.
来たわ
Found one.
見つけた
It's 12 o'clock.
時間よ
Unbelievable.
参ったな
Starting now, you'll listen to me.
ここからは私が決める
Trust me.
信じてよ
It's really good.
すごくおいしいから
Here, enjoy.
はい どうぞ
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
- ありがとう - どういたしまして
You don't eat coriander?
パクチーは食べないのか
[Loves spicy food; hates coriander]
[辛い物が好き パクチーが嫌い]
[Bad at sports; can't ride a bike]
[運動が苦手 自転車に乗れない]
She likes spicy food
辛い物が好き
and hates coriander.
パクチーが嫌い
This is so good.
おいしすぎる
Do you want some?
食べてみる？
No, thanks.
いや 結構だ
A grown man, but you can't handle spicy food?
大人なのに辛いのが苦手なんて
So weak.
弱いな
Let me trick him a bit.
騙してやろう
Have you ever heard of drinking wontons?
ワンタンを飲むって知ってる？
For wontons like these, with thin wrappers and just a little filling,
こういう皮が薄くて小さいのを
you can just drink them with the soup.
スープと一緒に飲むの
Won't that
彼女は
burn her mouth?
熱くないのか
Try it.
試してみて
Look closely.
よく見てて
It's after 12 o'clock now.
今は私の時間よ
You have to listen to me.
私の言うことを聞いてもらうわ
Finally, it's my turn to call the shots.
やっと私の番
First, a street food stall,
屋台の次は
and now she wants me to drink wontons.
ワンタンを飲ませるのか
Is she messing with me?
騙してないだろうな
It's so hot.
熱っ
Got you.
引っかかった
Is it good?
おいしい？
It's very hot.
熱い
So fussy.
ひ弱ね
Okay, fine.
わかったわ
I allow you to use a spoon.
スプーンを許可する
Revenge successful.
復讐大成功
Ms. Lin's going to show you
この林先生が
how rough the world can be.
社会の厳しさを教えてあげる
So what are we doing this afternoon?
じゃあ午後どうする？
Since you like checking the time so much...
そんなに時間を見るのが好きなら
I've got just the thing.
決めたわ
What is it?
何をするんだ？
According to the rules, you're not allowed to check the time.
ルールで時間は見ちゃダメよ
Or else you lose.
見たら負けだから
I'm going to drive you crazy with your own discipline.
あなたみたいな自律した人を 狂わせてあげる
Didn't you want to ride the duck boat?
アヒルボートに乗りたいんだろ
You won't check the time—
時間を見ないと
aren't you afraid of missing it?
乗り遅れないか？
No, I'm not.
平気よ
I don't care.
気にしないから
Does it bother you not to know the time?
時間見ないと辛いわね
Alright.
分かった
I can let you in on a little secret.
こっそり方法を教えてあげる
Actually,
実はね
the wind can also help us keep time.
風も時間を計ってくれるの
The flow of those ripples
この波紋の動きが
is time itself.
時間なのよ
You could call it
これは
the "Ripple Timing Method."
波紋時計って言うの
Tricking me again, huh?
また騙す気か
Yes, I am.
騙してるのよ
You don't believe me?
信じない？
Of course not.
当然だ
I'll show you.
やってみせるわ
Feel the ripples spreading out.
波紋の広がりを感じて
Close your eyes.
目を閉じて
Each ring
この一回りが
is about a second.
だいたい１秒よ
The spread of ripples
波紋の広がりは
isn't linear.
非線形だろ
You know quite a lot.
よく知ってるわね
It's really not easy to fool you.
騙しにくいわ
Come on.
ほら
You try it too.
あなたも試して
Imagine
想像してみて
this lake
この湖面が
is a canvas.
キャンバスで
The ripples are its brushstrokes.
波紋がその筆のタッチよ
On this canvas,
このキャンバスに
they paint it slowly.
ゆっくり絵を描くの
One second,
１秒
two seconds,
２秒
three seconds...
３秒
Why'd he go quiet?
どうして動かないの？
The ripples
波紋は
should have passed the lotuses by now.
蓮を越えたはずだ
That's right.
そうね
After the lotuses,
蓮を越えたら
they should reach the fallen leaves.
落ち葉のはず
Under the leaves,
落ち葉の下には
♪ With the evening breeze whispering in my ear ♪
♪ 夜風が耳元に 吹き寄せる告白 ♪
there are small fish.
小魚がいるの
Three more rings spread outward,
さらに外側に３回り
♪ Fireworks bloom across the sky ♪
♪ 空いっぱいの花火が 咲き誇る ♪
and then,
後ろを見て
they're about to reach the shore.
もうすぐ岸よ
♪ Shimmering in your eyes ♪
♪ あなたの瞳に映り込んで ♪
♪ And spreading into a gentle sea of stars ♪
♪ やさしさとなって広がる 星の海 ♪
♪ Every night ♪
♪ 毎晩 ♪
♪ I reach for starlight ♪
♪ 星の光に 手を伸ばす ♪
♪ Wandering through dreams with you ♪
♪ 君と夢の中を彷徨う ♪
♪ I follow the beat of my heart ♪
♪ 鼓動のリズムに乗せて ♪
♪ Like dust floating in the air ♪
♪ 宙を舞う塵のように ♪
♪ Because of your love ♪
♪ 君の愛が ♪
♪ I shine brilliantly ♪
♪ 私を輝かせる ♪
How was your nap?
よく寝れた？
When I was little and wouldn't sleep,
子供の頃 寝るのが嫌いで
my grandpa would bring me to the lake
おじいちゃんが湖に連れてきて
and trick me with this "Ripple Timing Method."
波紋時計で私を騙したの
I was tricking you.
騙したんだよ
You just realized it?
やっと気付いたのね
Your insomnia is pretty serious.
不眠症がひどいみたいね
I do have insomnia.
確かに不眠症だ
So?
だから？
So you should thank me even more.
だから私に感謝すべきよ
I repaid your cruelty with kindness
恨みを徳で報いて
and let you have such a wonderful late afternoon nap.
あんなに気持ちよく 夕寝させてあげたんだから
Coach Wang,
王コーチ
you lost.
あなたの負けよ
You checked the time.
時計を見たでしょ
You lost in the morning,
午前は君の負け
and I lost this afternoon.
午後は私の負け
So, it's a tie.
引き分けだな
Didn't we agree
約束しただろ
I'd only be the coach
君が勝ったら
if you won?
私がコーチになるって
Fine.
いいわ
We'll see who has the last laugh.
勝負はこれからよ
The day isn't over yet.
今日はまだ終わってない
I'll find a chance to turn things around.
逆転のチャンスを狙うわ
Didn't we agree
約束しただろ
I'd only be the coach
君が勝ったら
if you won?
私がコーチになるって
Let me think about
そうね
how to turn the tables.
どうやって逆転しようかな
[Killing time] [Stay strong]
[時間をつぶす] [強く生きる]
[Stay strong] [Too hard]
[つらすぎる]
[No. 8 High School Team, looking for a pro, come join the fight!]
[八高チーム 達人募集 すぐ開始]
No. 8 High School Team,
八高チーム
looking for a pro, come join the fight!
達人募集 すぐ開始
When I said "today,"
今日って言ったのは
I didn't just mean this morning.
午前中だけじゃないわ
Lin Lu,
林鹿
aren't you looking for a gaming pro?
ゲームの達人を探してたわよね
What a coincidence.
奇遇ね
I am one.
私がそうよ
Really?
マジで
Games? Anyone with hands can play.
ゲームなんて 朝飯前よ
Let's meet somewhere.
どこかで会って
I'll show you what I've got.
実力を見せてあげる
But
でも
you'll have to make a deal with me.
取引があるの
[Winfred]
[ウィンフレッド]
[Where are you?]
[どこにいる]
[The neighborhood park.]
[団地の公園よ]
[Slack Superstar]
[干物見習い]
Coach Wang,
王コーチ
today isn't over yet.
今日はまだ終わってない
I still have a chance
800キロカロリー消費
to hit 800 kcal.
まだチャンスはあるわ
Just you wait.
待ってて
[Cycling] [Average Pace: 9.3 km]
[サイクリング][平均ペース １キロメートルあたり9.3km]
[Coach Wang, today isn't over yet.]
[王コーチ 今日はまだ終わってない]
[I still have a chance to hit 800 kcal. Just you wait.]
[800キロカロリー消費 まだチャンスはあるわ]
Considering your fitness level,
君の体質を考慮して
I'll let you cut back on the workload.
運動量を減らすのを許可する
Watch out, there's someone ahead.
気をつけて 前に人いるよ
Run, run! Run to the safe zone.
走って走って 安地入らなきゃ
We're making it to the final circle.
いよいよ最終エリアよ
Only 23 players left.
残り23人しかいない
Northwest, northwest, northwest.
北西 北西よ
Enemy at 330 degrees.
330度の方向に敵がいる
Ms. Lin,
林先生
what do you think Coach would do
もしチートがコーチにバレたら
if he found out you were cheating?
どうなると思う？
So what?
別にいいじゃない
Winning is all that matters.
勝てばいいのよ
Who cares if he finds out?
構わないわ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
Oh no, oh no!
ヤバい ヤバい
There's a car behind us.
後ろに車が来た
Hide, hide.
隠れて 隠れて
Yes.
そう
Up ahead, up ahead.
前よ
There's loot in front.
前に宝物がある
Yeah, Spetsnaz Helmet.
特殊部隊のヘルメット
Ms. Lin, behind you.
林先生 後ろ
Thank you, Ms. Lin!
ありがとう 林先生
You're so good,
すっごく上手いね
Ms. Lin!
林先生
You cheated in our bet.
賭けでチートか
Miss Landlady.
大家さん
You lost.
君の負けだ
I actually got caught.
まさか見破られるとは
[Loves spicy food; hates coriander]
[辛い物が好き パクチーが嫌い]
[Bad at sports; can't ride a bike]
[運動が苦手 自転車に乗れない]
[Highly competitive; doesn't follow rules]
[競争心が強く ルールを守らない]
[Spade Q—Lin Wanxing]
[スペードのＱ 林晚星]
She clearly matches
テスト項目は
almost every item on the list...
ほとんど一致してるのに
♪ Two souls alike ♪
♪ 二つの魂が寄り添って ♪
♪ In the silent gravity ♪
♪ 静かな引力に導かれ ♪
But why do I have
どうしてこんな
♪ Cure my heart ♪
♪ 君のすべてで ♪
this strange feeling...
変な直感がするんだろう
♪ With every part of you ♪
♪ 私の孤独な心を 癒してくれた ♪
Could she not be the one?
まさか彼女は違う？
That man is a scammer.
あの男は詐欺師だ
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 言葉はそっと ♪
You're probably the only teacher
この辺りで
around here.
先生は君だけのはずだ
♪ Like a gentle stream ♪
♪ 優しい川のように流れて ♪
This isn't part of my job.
それは私の業務外よ
This is the first lesson for you—
今から最初のレッスンを始める
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 蛍のあかりが ♪
obey the referee's decisions.
審判の判定には従うこと
♪ Inside of a silky dream ♪
♪ 柔らかな夢へと舞い降りる ♪
Never mind.
まあいい
We're just going through the motions anyway.
どうせ ただの消化試合だし
I'll waive your rent.
家賃をタダにするわ
I'll waive it as long as you coach them.
指導してくれる期間はずっとよ
♪ We talked the whole night, breeze away ♪
♪ 夜通し語れば 夜風も静かに眠ってゆく ♪
I played a bit of a trick on you,
やり方は小細工だけど
but my wish for you to be the coach
コーチに来てほしいという気持ちは
is genuine.
本物なの
♪ Together we set out on a long journey ♪
♪ この長い道を ♪
Who is she, really?
彼女は一体誰だ
♪ The endless journey ♪
♪ どこまでも歩いていこう ♪
Coach Wang,
王コーチ
are you home?
ご在宅ですか
A bet is a bet,
負けは認めるよ
Miss Landlady.
大家さん
But I still want to
でも まだ
make a last-ditch effort.
あがいてみたいの
How?
どうあがく？
By offering you a fair trade.
等価交換よ
How long have you had insomnia?
不眠症はいつから？
I have it all figured out.
もう考えたわ
How about this?
こうしよう
You come coach at Hongjing No. 8 High School,
あなたが宏景第八高校の コーチになって
and I'll help you with your insomnia.
私が不眠を和らげるのはどう？
I swear
約束する
I'll make you sleep
絶対に
deeply and peacefully.
安らかに眠らせてあげる
Lifestyle habits alone
生活習慣だけでは
aren't enough to prove anything.
問題は説明できない
Perhaps through more interaction,
他の関わりから
I can uncover more of the truth.
真実を証明できるかも
Your proposal...
君の提案
has persuaded me.
心に響いた
So,
つまり
you agree?
引き受けてくれるの？
Deal.
交渉成立だ
So the strong really do have
強者の心理的優位
a psychological edge.
やっぱりそうね
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ？
It's a concept in psychology:
心理学の言葉よ
the psychological edge of the strong.
強者の心理的優位
You've always been the stronger one in your life.
あなたは常に生活の中で強者よ
A truly strong person
本当の強者は
doesn't need to crush the weak to prove their strength.
弱者を叩いて証明する必要はない
On the contrary,
逆に
they demonstrate
譲り合いを通して
control through yielding.
支配力を示すことができるの
So, I thought
だから私は
I still had a chance.
まだ希望があると思ったの
Coach Wang, I'm really not trying to manipulate you.
王コーチ 罠じゃないわよ
Think about it.
考えてみて
Actually,
実は
the moment you made eye contact with those kids yesterday,
昨日子供たちと目を合わせた時
you'd already made your decision,
もう決めていたんでしょ
right?
違う？
Thank you, Coach Wang Fa.
ありがとう 王法コーチ
Welcome to the Hongjing No. 8 High School football team.
宏景第八高校のサッカー部へ ようこそ
Fu Xinshu, Fu Xinshu,
付新書
help me create a group chat with everyone.
みんなでグループを作って
Hello, Ms. Dan, I'm here again.
丹さん また来たよ
You're here? Have a seat inside.
いらっしゃい 中へどうぞ
-Come in and find a table. -Come in.
- どうぞ 中へお入りください - 中へお入りください
-Feiyang, go easy on the chili. -Help yourself.
- 飛揚 唐辛子を少なめに - 自分でやってください
No problem.
分かった
Auntie, please keep an eye on him for me, thanks.
おばさん 見張っててください ありがとう
-Sure. -Come help me with this.
- わかりました - 誰かそれ取ってくれよ
Uncle, let me help you.
おじさん 手伝いますよ
I fried these myself!
僕が揚げたんだ
-You made them yourself? -You fried these?
- 僕が揚げたんだ - 自分で？
-Then I'm gonna pass. -Are you sure?
- それなら食べない - 本当に？
Let me be the guinea pig.
まず俺が毒見してやる
I c-can't eat it, not even a bite.
全然食べられない
-Stop fussing around. -Hurry up and eat.
- もう動かなくていいぞ - さっさと食えよ
Feiyang, they're actually pretty good!
飛揚 上手に揚がってる
Of course. My cooking speaks for itself.
当然だろ 僕の腕を疑うな
Let me try. Let me try.
味見させて
Are you complimenting him or making fun of him?
それ褒めてんのか けなしてんのか
You ate the spicy ones.
辛いの食べてるじゃん
I saw that too.
俺も見た
Delicious. Delicious.
うまい
[Group Chat]
[グループチャット]
Yes, Ginger Duck.
そう 姜母鴨だ
I didn't overuse that trick, did I?
この松葉づえは大げさじゃないだろ
Didn't I teach you already?
教えただろ
Fu started a new group chat.
付が新しいグループ作った
Everyone, take a look.
みんな 見てみろ
Ms. Lin joined too.
林先生も入ってる
[Little Savage Tribe]
[野人部落]
She even renamed the group Little Savage Tribe.
グループ名を「野人部落」に変えた
What's "Little Savage" supposed to mean?
野人って どういう意味だ
[Little Savage Tribe]
[野人部落]
I hereby announce
重大発表
-you have a coach now. -Wait.
- これからコーチがいるよ - え？
Everyone, assemble tomorrow
明日集合
and start training.
練習開始よ
Really?
マジかよ
Former Nanton FC Youth Academy Coach?
元サウサンプトンのユースコーチ
Nanton!
元サウサンプトンだぞ
No way.
あり得ない
I'm not seeing things, am I?
見間違いじゃないよな
-Really? -Are you joking?
- 本当？ - 冗談じゃない？
A former Nanton youth coach is going to train us?
元サウサンプトンのユースコーチが 俺たちを教える？
Ms. Lin, this joke isn't funny.
先生 その冗談は笑えません
It's not a joke.
冗談じゃない
I'll have your coach come out
コーチに出てきてもらって
and confirm it himself.
正体を確かめましょ
I'm the real deal.
本物だ
Ms. Lin, did you kidnap him or something?
林先生 脅したんでしょ
Either leave the group or treat everyone to milk tea.
グループ抜けるかお茶おごるか どっちか選んで
Welcome, Coach.
コーチ 歓迎します
+1.
賛成
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
林先生 ありがとうございます
-Keep your word. -+1.
- 約束を守る -賛成
-Remember to come to training tomorrow.
- 明日練習に来いよ - 賛成
-See you guys there. -+1.
- 必ず来てね
This one again.
またこれ
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team Roster]
[宏景第八高校 サッカー部員リスト]
Coach Wang,
王コーチ
here's the file with player profiles.
部員の資料を渡しておくわ
See you tomorrow.
また明日
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team Roster]
[宏景第八高校 サッカー部員リスト]
Okay.
はい
Why name it the "Little Savage Tribe"?
なぜ「野人部落」にした？
No reason.
何となく
It's just a nickname.
ニックネームよ
You prickly QR Code.
ツンデレＱＲコード男
I'm counting on you from here.
あとは頼んだわよ
Do your best.
頑張ってね
You're back from work.
バイトから帰ったわ
Why are you still at it this late?
こんな遅くまでやってるのか
Let me help.
ほら
I collected quite a bit today.
今日はいっぱい拾ったの
Sort them out now,
整理して
and I can sell them first thing tomorrow morning.
明日の朝に売りに行くわ
-Here. -Come on.
- ほら これ - ほら
Move your leg.
足どけて
Okay. Okay.
良い
Right, just pile it up here.
そう ここに積んで
All done, Grandma.
おばあさん
You've worked hard. Go back and rest.
お疲れさま 早く休んで
You've worked hard, Grandma.
お疲れさま おばあさん
[Serenity Leads to Vision]
[寧静致遠]
Okay, go to sleep early too.
あなたも早くお休み
Get up early tomorrow.
明日は早起きしなさい
I'll make you red bean porridge.
小豆粥を作ってあげるから
Okay, Grandma.
うん おばあさん
Good night.
おやすみ
[Mom, we tied with Ning'an Experimental School.]
[母さん 寧安実験学校と 同点だったよ]
Congratulations.
おめでとう
Xinshu, there's one more thing.
書 もう一つあるの
Remember I told you
前に話したでしょ
I've been feeling unwell lately?
最近 体調が悪いの
I've booked an appointment with a specialist.
専門医の予約を取ったのよ
Has it gotten worse, Mom?
悪くなったのか 母さん
What day is your appointment?
いつ病院に行くの
Do you want me to come with you?
付き添おうか
No need.
大丈夫よ
It's just that I'm a bit tight on money.
ただ ちょっとお金がなくて
[Transfer amount: 3,000]
[送金額 ６万円]
Mom, your health comes first.
母さん 体が第一だよ
If you're short on money, just tell me.
お金のことは心配しないで
[Qiuhua Community Health Center]
[秋華街道社区病院]
[Hongjing City Bus Card Top-up Center]
[宏景市バスチャージセンター]
[Guan Minjie]
[関敏婕]
[Qiuhua Community Health Center]
[秋華街道社区病院]
[Mom, we tied with Ning'an Experimental School.]
[母さん 寧安実験学校と 同点だったよ]
Congratulations.
おめでとう
When do you think Coach will get here?
コーチはいつ来るかな
[Warmly welcoming Coach Wang Fa]
[王法コーチ]
[to join the Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[宏景八高サッカー部へようこそ]
I can't wait.
もう待ちきれない
I can't believe something this good
こんな良いこと
actually happened to us.
俺たちに巡ってくるなんて
You hit me for real?
マジで叩くなよ
-Come on. -Go away.
- ほら - あっち行って
What time is it?
今 何時だ
Ten to three.
２時50分
That's the third time you've asked in 10 minutes.
10分で３回目だぞ
Come on, bro.
おいおい
Guys,
みんな
if he's even one minute late,
もし１分でも遅刻したら
we're leaving.
すぐ帰ろうぜ
We agreed to meet at three.
コーチとの約束は３時だ
Even I know to arrive early for something like this.
こんな時 俺だって早めに来るのに
He's obviously not being sincere.
誠意がないのが見え見えだろ
Maybe he never intended to come at all.
最初から来る気なんてなくて
Just messing with us.
からかわれてるだけかも
True.
確かに
Qin Ao, it's not time yet.
秦敖 まだ時間じゃない
-A former Nanton youth coach. -What?
- サウサンプトンユースの大コーチだぜ - 何してるんだ？
Weren't you so excited you couldn't sleep last night?
昨夜は楽しみで眠れなかったくせに
I'm just going to buy a soda.
ジュースを買いに行くだけだ
What?
なんだよ
I'm not late, am I?
遅刻してないだろ
He's really here.
本当に来た
Everyone, over here.
全員来い
Line up.
並べ
Go, go, go.
行くぞ
Hurry, hurry.
急げ
Line up, line up.
ちゃんと並べ
Come on, line up.
ほら 整列しろ
Hurry up.
急げ
I'm Wang Fa.
私が王法だ
Midfielder Fu Xinshu.
付新書 ミッドフィルダー
Hello, Coach.
コーチ お願いします
Forward Chen Jianghe.
陳江河 フォワード
Forward Qin Ao.
秦敖 フォワード
Here.
はい
Defender Lin Lu.
林鹿 ディフェンダー
Defender Qi Liang.
祁亮 ディフェンダー
Here.
はい
Defender Yu Ming.
俞明 ディフェンダー
Hello, Coach.
お願いします
Defender Zheng Feiyang.
鄭飛陽 ディフェンダー
Here.
到着
Midfielder Zheng Ren.
鄭仁 ミッドフィルダー
Hello, Coach.
お願いします
Midfielder Zhi Hui.
智会 ミッドフィルダー
Goalkeeper Feng Suo.
馮鎖 ゴールキーパー
Hello, Coach.
お願いします
One player, Chen Weidong, is absent.
もう一人の選手 陳衛東がまだ来ていません
He's training with the track team.
陸上部で練習中です
As for our future training schedule,
今後の練習計画だが
I'll coach the team from 3:00 to 5:00 every afternoon.
午後３時から５時まで指導する
If anything changes,
詳細については
Ms. Lin will notify you.
林先生が知らせる
Alright, boys.
はい みんな
Now that Coach Wang Fa has joined us,
王法コーチが加わったからには
I believe our Hongjing No. 8 High School football team
私たち宏景八高のサッカー部は
will rise again, grow stronger,
必ずまた強くなって
and reach new heights of glory.
輝きを取り戻せるわ
Yeah! Great!
はい
-Thank you, Coach.
- ありがとうございます コーチ
Ms. Lin, your idioms are quite old-school.
林先生の語彙は古典的だな
Does the great coach have anything else to say?
コーチ 他に何かある？
I'm just a temporary coach,
私はしばらくの間だけ
filling in for a short time.
君たちの臨時コーチになる
That's still great.
それでも十分だ
Even just half an hour of your coaching
30分でも教えてもらえれば
would be worth it for us,
俺たちの得だ
right?
そうだろ
Then...
じゃあ
let's get to training.
練習を始めるぞ
-Let's go. -Wait.
- ちょっと歩き回ろう - ちょっと待って
Shouldn't we do something
ちょっとした
to mark the occasion?
セレモニーをしないか
What do you mean?
どういうことだ
Sign a football?
サインボールだ
When we all become famous someday,
将来 俺たちが有名になったら
this'll be priceless.
これはプライスレスだぜ
Captain, you go first.
キャプテンからどうぞ
-I'll go first then. -Okay.
- じゃあ私が先に行きますね - わかりました
-I'll go first. -Come on.
- 私が先に行くよ - さあ
[Fu Xinshu]
[付新書]
Here.
来る
♪ Who isn't going through nights of darkness and confusion ♪
♪ 誰もが夜と迷いの中を 生きている ♪
Me first, me first.
俺が先だ
[Zheng Ren]
[鄭仁]
♪ Stumbling, covered in wounds, losing direction ♪
♪ 傷だらけで 転びながら 立ち尽くす ♪
[Feng Suo]
[馮鎖]
♪ Wandering alone, gaining strength through pain ♪
♪ 孤独に彷徨い 痛みの果てに強くなる ♪
[Zheng]
[鄭]
Now it really feels like a football team with star players.
スター選手みたいだな
Totally.
うん
♪ Riding the wind, chasing an unknown horizon ♪
♪ 风に乗り 未知なる明日へ駆け抜ける ♪
My turn, my turn.
次は俺だ
♪ Looking up, dreaming side by side of great ideals ♪
♪ 見上げてごらん 共に描いた大いなる夢 ♪
[Lin Lu]
[林鹿]
Boss, sign next to mine.
兄貴 隣に書いてよ
♪ The vast world awaits youth to arrive ♪
♪ 広がる世界が 少年の訪れを待っている ♪
Don't be so quick to forget.
喉元過ぎれば熱さを忘れるな
It's for Fu's sake.
付のために
♪ If facing every storm is ♪
♪ 風浪に立ち向かう ことこそが ♪
I'll just scribble something.
適当に書くだけだ
♪ What it takes to grow ♪
♪ 成長と呼ぶのなら ♪
You're the one taking it most seriously.
一番真剣に書いてるくせに
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 僕は抗い 流れに逆らい ♪
[Qin]
[秦]
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 派手に暴れてやるさ ♪
[Qin Ao]
[秦敖]
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ たとえ前路が遥か遠くとも ♪
It's really big.
それは確かにとても大きい
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 誰も僕を止められはしない ♪
Quit pretending, dude.
とぼけるなよ
Here, pen.
ペン
So annoying.
うっせえな
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ すべての迷いを打ち破り ♪
Look at his goofy face.
馬鹿な
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 自分の光を追い求める ♪
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 嵐の中で 強くしなやかな翼を広げ ♪
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 誰も拍手をくれなくとも ♪
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 全力で突き進むだけ ♪
Coach.
コーチ
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 誰もいない戦場で ♪
♪ I grow stronger with a resounding voice ♪
♪ 高らかに息吹を響かせろ ♪
It's not like you're signing away your soul.
身売り証文じゃないわよ
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 重ねた傷跡のすべてを ♪
Just a sweet memento of our friendly cooperation.
友好と協力の記念よ
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 栄光の勲章にするんだ ♪
♪ If facing every storm is ♪
♪ 風浪に立ち向かう ことこそが ♪
♪ What it takes to grow ♪
♪ 成長と呼ぶのなら ♪
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 僕は抗い 流れに逆らい ♪
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 派手に暴れてやるさ ♪
Alright, boys.
はい みんな
It's about time.
時間だわ
Hurry up and go to training.
早く練習に行って
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ たとえ前路が遥か遠くとも ♪
[Feng Suo] [Qin Ao]
[馮鎖][秦敖]
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 誰も僕を止められはしない ♪
Okay.
はい
Everyone, let's go train.
全員集合 練習だ
-Okay, okay. -Let's go.
- わかった - 行こう
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ すべての迷いを打ち破り ♪
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 自分の光を追い求める ♪
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 嵐の中で 強くしなやかな翼を広げ ♪
Coach Wang Fa.
王法コーチ
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 誰も拍手をくれなくとも ♪
Your whistle.
あなたの笛
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 全力で突き進むだけ ♪
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 誰もいない戦場で ♪
♪ I grow stronger with a resounding voice ♪
♪ 高らかに息吹を響かせろ ♪
[Feng Suo]
[馮鎖]
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 重ねた傷跡のすべてを ♪
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 栄光の勲章にするんだ ♪
Coach,
コーチ
what are we training today?
今日の練習は？
Quick short passing combos,
ショートパス？
or Nanton's signature high press?
それともサウサンプトンの ハイプレス？
Hurry up and give the orders.
早く指示をくださいよ
They're all waiting.
みんな待ってるわ
Captain, lead the team.
キャプテンが率いて
Run laps.
ランニングだ
Run laps?
ランニング？
Okay.
はい
Everyone, gather by the edge of the field.
グラウンドの端に集まれ
Let's go!
行くぞ
Let's go, Boss.
行こうぜ 兄貴
Sorry, I'm late.
すみません 遅れました
Fall in.
列に戻れ
Quick march.
走れ
I wonder what he's up to.
一体何を考えてるのかしら
Fu, that should be enough running, right?
付 もういいだろ
It should be.
もういいはずだ
Okay, everyone, stop for a second.
よし みんな いったん止まって
Alright.
分かった
I'll go ask.
聞いてくる
Coach,
コーチ
we've finished three warm-up laps.
ウォーミングアップの3周は 終わりました
So what's next?
次は？
Keep running.
走り続けろ
Okay.
はい
Keep running!
まだ走るぞ
Looks like he's playing mind games.
心理戦を仕掛けてるみたいね
Come on, let's go.
行くぞ
Why?
どういうことだ
-Keep running. -Keep up, keep up!
- 走り続けろ - ついていけ
I never get tired of this snack.
このお菓子 飽きないわね
Don't mind if I do.
遠慮するな
Not again.
また？
You took the whole bag like it was only natural?
全部取っておいて よく平気でいられるわね
Playing dumb, huh?
とぼけてる？
Can we talk about something?
相談があるんだけど
Go ahead.
言ってみろ
A bag of snacks—
このお菓子は
my snacks—
私のものだから
I should get two-thirds,
私が３分の２で
and you get one-third.
あなたは３分の１よ
So much for "friendly cooperation", huh?
これが友好と協力か
Using my words against me?
言い負かされた
Alright.
分かったわ
Half and half, then.
じゃあ半分ずつ
I'll show my sincerity with fairness.
公平さで誠意を表すわ
Pour them out then.
じゃあ出して
I'll count.
数えるから
Seriously? What's wrong with this guy?
何なのこの人
I poured...
はい
Thanks.
どうも
I feel your sincerity.
誠意があるな
I'm so pissed.
むかつく
Eat, eat.
食べて
Hope you'll be a little nicer to the kids.
あの子たちに優しくしてね
I'll consider it your fee.
お駄賃代わりよ
Formation.
隊形を崩すな
Why are we still running?
まだ走るのか
How many laps have we done?
これで何周目だ？
I'm exhausted.
もうヘトヘトだ
Wen Chengye?
文成業
What's he doing here?
どうしてここにいるの
I can't run anymore.
もう走れない
-Stop talking. Focus on your breathing. -Fu.
- 話すな 息を吸え - 付
Fu, do we still need to run?
付 まだ走るのか
Why don't you go ask?
聞いてきてくれよ
-Yeah. Go. -Yeah. Go ask him.
- うん 早く行って - うん 早く
Go ask quickly.
早く聞いてこいよ
Okay, everyone, stop.
よし みんな止まれ
I'll ask again.
もう一度聞いてくる
Coach, we've done 10 laps already.
コーチ もう10周です
Do we keep going?
まだ続けますか
Yes.
走れ
Still running?
まだ走るの？
Should I ask?
聞きに行く？
-Alright. -Forget it.
もういいわ
I'm just a layman here.
私はただの素人だし
I'd better trust Coach on this.
コーチに従うべきね
Guys!
みんな
Keep running.
走り続けろ
More laps?
まだ走るのかよ
Hang in there.
もうひと踏ん張りだ
-Come on! Come on! -I can't run anymore.
- 頑張って - もう走れない
-My legs are about to cramp. -Let's go.
- 足がつりそうだ - 走るぞ
Are they trying to kill us?
やってられるか
-Feng Suo, keep up! -No, I seriously can't run anymore!
- 馮鎖 ついてこい - ダメ もう走れない
Hang in there!
- 頑張れ
-Keep up. -Just a little longer.
- 頑張れ もうひと踏ん張りだ
Let's stop running.
もうやめようぜ
Keep up, come on.
ついてこい
What lap are we on?
今 何周目だよ
Hang in there.
頑張れ
Will this ever end? We've been running forever.
いつまで走らせる気だ
I'm about to drop dead.
もう死にそうだ
How long has it been?
もうどれくらい経ったの
Still going?
まだ走ってる
I can see they're hitting their limit.
みんな体力の限界みたい
How much longer are we supposed to run?
いつまで走るんだよ
Hang in there, boys.
頑張って みんな
Captain, I need a break.
キャプテン 少し休ませてくれ
-No stopping. -Let me walk a bit.
- ダメ - 行こう
Go.
歩く
-No. -Keep up. Keep up.
- ダメだ - ついていけ ついていけ
What exactly are you trying to do?
どういう意味だ
Nothing.
他意はない
Then is that all we're training today?
今日はずっとこれか
Yes.
これだけか
What's the point of long-distance jogging?
長時間のジョギングに 何の意味が？
It won't improve our fitness at all.
体力向上にならないぜ
-Yeah. -Exactly.
- そうだ
Long-distance jogging
長時間のジョギングは
will also affect your speed and explosiveness.
スピードと瞬発力に悪影響だ
So he's using reverse psychology.
挑発してるんだわ
You never wanted to coach us in the first place, did you?
指導する気がないんだろ
Is this what Nanton's advanced training is—
サウサンプトンの高度な練習って
just making players run?
ただ走るだけかよ
Exactly.
そうだ
Are you kidding us?
ふざけてるのか
I thought we were shooting a movie—
映画の撮影かと思ったぜ
running lap after lap.
何度も何度も
Playing us for fools, huh?
馬鹿にしてるんだろ
Fine.
いいぜ
We're out!
もうやらない
Coach,
コーチ
you never wanted to train us in the first place,
最初から指導する気なんて
did you?
なかったんですよね
So you think this is on me too?
私の問題だと思うか？
Why bother asking him?
聞くだけ無駄だ
Isn't it obvious?
明白だろ
We're not good enough for a coach from Nanton.
俺たちはサウサンプトンの名コーチに 釣り合わないってさ
Do you get it now?
分かったか
Don't look at me.
私を見ないで
You'll have to work out the coordination
コーチとチームのすり合わせは
with your coach on your own.
自分たちで解決するしかない
I told you so.
だから言っただろ
They were never worth trusting.
あいつらは信用できない
Reality just slapped you in the face, huh?
面目丸つぶれだ
A coach from Nanton's youth academy— why would someone like him
サウサンプトンユース レベルのコーチが
ever think we're worth coaching?
俺たちを相手にするわけない
You talk too much.
お前は口数が多い
Would it kill you to say less?
少し黙ってられないのか
Yes!
無理
-Fu.
付
-See? -Fu!
- ほら - 付
Fu, where are you going?
付 どこへ行くんだ
Fu Xinshu!
付新書
What's going on?
どうした
Why did Fu leave?
なんで行っちゃうんだ
Ms. Lin.
林先生
What's wrong?
どうしたの
Did Coach Wang leave any explanation?
コーチは何も言わなかったですか？
And you didn't ask us to go back and continue training.
先生も練習に戻れと言わなかったし
That was your own decision.
これはあなたたちの決定よ
I have no right to interfere.
先生に干渉する権利はない
That's true.
そうですね
I was overthinking it.
考えすぎでした
You really don't need to interfere.
先生が口出しする必要はありません
You, just like Coach Wang,
先生もコーチも
must think
どうせ僕たちが
we're not good enough.
ふさわしくないと思ってるんでしょ
It's not like that.
そんなことない
Coach Wang didn't sign the football,
コーチはボールに サインしませんでした
and neither did you.
先生もしていませんでした
Why?
どうして
That's because...
それは…
I'm just a team supervisor.
私がただの監督の先生だから
Is that really the reason?
本当にそうですか
Isn't it because,
本当は
in your and Coach Wang's minds,
先生とコーチの心の中では
the football team has always just been us,
サッカー部は僕たちだけで
and there's no need for you to be part of it?
あなたたちは必要ないって
Makes sense.
そうですよね
How we play,
僕たちがどんなプレーをして
whether we win or lose,
勝とうが負けようが
has nothing to do with you anyway, right?
先生には関係ないですもんね
Sorry to bother you, Ms. Lin.
お邪魔しました 先生
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 何も怖くない ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 君がいるから ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 微かな光が交差して ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 星のように煌めく ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 君の元へ駆け出して ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 恐れず前へ進もう ♪
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪肩を並べて♪
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ ありのままの僕らへ ♪
♪ Amid the storm ♪
♪嵐の真っ只中で♪